<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
<spell><name>Absorb Elements</name>
<level>1</level>
<school>A</school>
<time>1 reaction, which you take when you take acid, cold, fire, lightning, or thunder damage</time>
<range>Self</range>
<components>S</components>
<duration>1 round</duration>
<text>The spell captures some of the incoming energy, lessening its effect on you and storing it for your next melee attack. You have resistance to the triggering damage type until the s tart of your next turn. Also, the first time you hit with a melee attack on your next turn, the target takes an extra 1d6 damage of the triggering type, and the spell ends.\n\n⇪At Higher Levels⇪\nWhen you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the extra damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 1st.</text>
</spell>
<spell><name>Catapult</name>
<level>1</level>
<school>T</school>
<time>1 action</time>
<range>60 feet</range>
<components>S</components>
<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
<text>Choose one object weighing 1 to 5 pounds within range that isn't being worn or carried. The object flies in a straight line up to 90 feet in a direction you choose before falling to the ground, stopping early if it impacts against a solid surface. If the object would strike a creature, that creature must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, the object strikes the target and stops moving. When the object strikes something, the object and what it strikes each take 3d8 bludgeoning damage.\n\n⇪At Higher Levels⇪\nWhen you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the maximum weight of objects that you can target with this spell increases by 5 pounds, and the damage increases by 1d8, for each slot level above 1st.</text>
</spell>
<spell><name>Create Bonfire</name>
<level>0</level>
<school>C</school>
<time>1 action</time>
<range>60 feet</range>
<components>V, S</components>
<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
<text>You create a bonfire on ground that you can see within range. until the spell ends, the magic bonfire fills a5-foot cube. Any creature in the bonfire's apce when you cast the spell must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or take 1d8 fire damage. A creature must also make the saving throw when it moces into the bonfire's space for the first time on a turn or ends its turn there.\n\nThe bonfire ignites flammable objects in its area that aren't being worn or carried.\n\nThe spell's damage increase by 1d8 when you reach 5th level (2d8), 11th level (3d8), and 17th level (4d8).</text>
</spell>
<spell><name>Frostbite</name>
<level>0</level>
<school>EV</school>
<time>1 action</time>
<range>60 feet</range>
<components>V, S</components>
<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
<text>You cause numbing frost to form on one creature that you can see within range . The target must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, the target takes 1d6 cold damage, and it has disadvantage on the next weapon attack roll it makes before the end of its next turn.\n\nThe spell's damage increases by 1d6 when you reach 5th level 92d6), 11th level (3d6), and 17th level (4d6).</text>
</spell>
<spell><name>Magic Stone</name>
<level>0</level>
<school>T</school>
<time>1 bonus action</time>
<range>Touch</range>
<components>V, S</components>
<duration>1 minute</duration>
<text>You touch one to three pebbles and imbue them with magic. You or someone else can make a ranged spell attack with one of the pebbles by throwing it or hurling it with a sling. If thrown, a pebble has a range of 60 feet. If someone else attacks with a pebble, that attacker adds your spellcasting ability modifier, not the attacker's, to the attack roll. On a hit, the target takes bludgeoning damage equal to 1d6 + your spellcasting ability modifier. Whether the attack hits or misses, the spell then ends on the stone.\n\nIf you cast this spell again, the spell ends on any pebbles still affected by your previous casting.</text>
</spell>
<spell><name>Snare</name>
<level>1</level>
<school>A</school>
<time>1 minute</time>
<range>Touch</range>
<components>S, M (25 feet of rope, which the spell consumes)</components>
<duration>8 hours</duration>
<text>As you cast this spell , you use the rope to create a circle with a 5-foot radius on the g r ou nd or the floor. When you finish casting, the rope disappears and the circle becomes a magic trap.\n\nThis trap is nearly invisible, requiring a successful Intelligence (Investigation) check against your spell save DC to be discerned.\n\nThe trap triggers when a Small, Medium, or Large creature moves onto the ground or t he floor in the spell's radius. That creature must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or be magically hoisted into the air, leaving it hanging upside down 3 feet above the ground or the floor. The creature is restrained there until the spell ends.\n\nA restrained creature can make a Dexterity saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. Alternatively, the creature or someone else who can reach it can use an action to make an Intelligence (Arcana) check against your spell save DC. On a success, th e r estrained effect ends.\n\nAfter the trap is triggered, the spell ends when no creature is restrained by it.</text>
</spell>
<spell><name>Thunderclap</name>
<level>0</level>
<school>EV</school>
<time>1 action</time>
<range>5 feet</range>
<components>S</components>
<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
<text>You create a burst of thunderous sound that can be heard up to 100 feet away. Each creature within range, other than you, must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or take 1d6 thunder damage.\n\nThe spell's damage increases by 1d6 when you reach 5th level (2d6), 11th level (3d6), and 17th level (4d6).</text>
</spell>
</compendium>